Preliminary Inventory to the W. Randolph Burgess Papers, 1913-1978
Hoover Institution Archives
W. Randolph Burgess Papers,
1913-1978
80183
Burgess, W. Randolph (Warren Randolph), 1889-
44 manuscript boxes, 3 oversize boxes (19.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, speeches and writings, minutes, memoranda, printed matter, memorabilia, and photographs, relating to international trade and finance, banking and American monetary policy, the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, the Atlantic Council, the Atlantic Treaty Association, and American foreign relations with Europe.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Access Points
Atlantic Council of the United States.; Atlantic Treaty Association.; North Atlantic Treaty Organization.; Commerce.; International finance.; Europe.; Europe--Foreign relations--United States.; United States--Politics and government.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Foreign relations--Europe.
Container List
- Printed matter (Box 1)
- Printed matter (Box 2)
- International Monetary Fund
- Monetary Committee (of the Atlantic Council of the U.S.)
  - General
  - Meetings, New York City, 1972
  - Papers distributed
  - Statement
  - Meetings, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Basic Causes of Present Monetary Problems, 1972
- Atlantic Institute
  - Conference, Royaumont, 1966
  - Atlantic studies meeting, 1965
  - Atlantic colloquium subcommittee, 1965
  - Inter-university conference, Stanford University, 1965
  - Atlantic studies conference, 1964
  - Atlantic studies meeting, 1967
  - Capital markets conference, Cannes, 1967
- Biographical sketch
- Per Jacobsson Foundation
  - General
  - Lecture, 1969
  - Dinner, 1969
- Johns Hopkins University - School of Advanced International Studies
- Per Jacobsson Foundation (Box 4)
  - General
  - Jacobsson family
  - 1974
  - Meeting, Washington, 1971
  - 1973
- Economic Working Group (of the Atlantic Council of the U.S.)
- Huntley, James R., 1971
- Europe and America: The Next Ten Years, 1970 - Correspondence
- Order of the Hospital of St. John of Jerusalem (Box 5)
- Jordan, Robert S.
- Per Jacobsson Foundation
  - Meeting, Tokyo, 1974
  - 1975
- Atlantic Council of the U.S.
  - Policy statement
  - Belgian resolution
  - NATO Committee
  - Committee on Trade, Monetary and Corporate Policy
    - General
    - Monetary Modernization, 1965
  - Non-Military Functions of NATO, 1965
  - Committee on Atlantic Economic Cooperation
  - The Atlantic Monetary Community, 1968
  - Business program
- North Atlantic Treaty Organization
- Direct Investment Conference, 1969
- Atlantic Institute
  - Tuthill, John, 1969
  - Tuthill, John, Karl Mundt, and parliamentarians
- Direct Investment Conference, 1969 - Summary (Box 6)
- A. T. & T. economics meetings
- Men and Institutions, 1964
- NATO from an Outside Perspective, 1967
- Cherishing Public Credit, 1963
- The Economic Consequences of de Gaulle, 1963
- Are Changes in the NATO Treaty Necessary or Desirable? 1965
- Strategic Notes
- Per Jacobsson Foundation - Booklets
- International Monetary Fund - Joint Bank/Fund Committee on Executive Directors' Remuneration, 1969
- Hostels
- Foreign Policy Association
  - 1969
  - 1970
- Atlantic Treaty Association - William F. Langdon (Great Britain)
- Europe meeting (of the Atlantic Treaty Association and Atlantic Council of the U.S.), 1970
- Emergency Committee for a Reappraisal of U.S. Overseas Information Policies and Programs
- Claremont Colleges
- Action program and summary statement, Geneva, 1966
- NATO Strategy, 1966
- Statement by NATO Committee of the Atlantic Council of the U.S., 1966
- U.S. Policy in the Atlantic Community, 1966
- Keys to Continuing Prosperity, 1965 (Box 7)
- Ford Foundation
- Atlantic Colleges
- Foreign Policy Association
- K
- Kennedy, David
- Europe and America: The Next Ten Years, 1970
  - Letter to directors of the Atlantic Council of the U.S.
  - Publicity copies - Letters
  - Directors - Correspondence
  - Congressmen - Correspondence
  - Free copies and flyers - Lists
  - Pre-publication correspondence
- Review of Richard H. Meyer, Bankers' Diplomacy, 1970
- Youth
- References and data
- Tuthill, John W., 1973
- Huntley, James R.
- Federal Reserve Bank, 1975
- Trade, 1975
- Environment Conference, Washington, 1971
- Eisenhower, Dwight D.
- After the Energy Hurricane, 1974 (Box 8)
- Burns, Arthur
- A. I. E. S. E. C.
- American Philosophical Society
- American Assembly
- American Bankers Association
- Committee for Economic Development
- Council on Foreign Relations
- Atlantic Treaty Association
  - Hellenic Atlantic Treaty Association (Greece)
  - Association for Western Cooperation (Iceland)
  - Lombardo, Ivan Matteo (Italy)
  - Atlantische Commissie (Netherlands)
  - Berdal, Eivind (Norway)
  - Comissao Portuguesa do Atlantico (Portugal)
  - British Atlantic Committee (United Kingdom)
- Columbia University Oral History Research Office
- Leadership: The Vital Ingredient, 1970
- Europe and America: The Next Ten Years, 1970 - Revisions
- Agriculture study, 1972
- Foreign Policy Association, 1971
- Gemmell, Ted
- Committee on Foreign Affairs (of the U.S. House of Representatives) - Subcommittee on International Organizations and Movements
- First National City Bank
  - 1965-1969
  - 1971
- Strausz-Hupe, Robert, and Metropolitan Club
- Atlantic Institute, 1973
- Chronological
  - January-March 1972
  - April-June 1972
  - July-December 1973
  - January-June 1974
  - July-December 1975 (Box 9)
  - January-July 1976
- Buchan, Alastair, Crisis Management, 1966
- Europe-America Conference, Amsterdam, 1973
- Atlantic Institute
  - Huntley, James R.
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot
  - Tuthill, John W.
    - 1972
    - 1971
    - 1970
    - Meeting, Pittsburgh, 1969
- Federal Reserve Bank
- Atlantic Treaty Association
  - Spaak, Paul Henri
  - Assembly, Paris, 1975
  - Meeting, Brussels, 1973
  - 1971
  - Seminar, Norfolk, 1973
  - Atlantic Information Center for Teachers
  - Information Committee
  - Meeting, Istanbul, 1972 (Box 10)
  - Meeting with Otto Pick, 1970
  - Roberts, Sir Frank
  - 1970
  - Constitution
  - Resolutions and Declaration of Rome, 1965
  - Sala, Antoine (France)
  - Mahias, Pierre
  - Deutsche Atlantische Gesellschaft e. V. (Germany)
  - Gladwyn, Lord
  - Association Francaise pour la Communaute Atlantique (France)
  - Emanuelli, Pierre
  - Association Atlantique Belge (Belgium)
  - Pirenne, J. H. (Belgium)
  - Zeeland, Paul van (Belgium)
  - Atlantic Council of Canada (Canada)
  - Markussen, Per (Denmark)
- L
- The Impact of the Internationalization of Production on U.S. Labor, 1971
- Mc
- International Management and Development Institute - Gene Bradley
- Mally, Gerhard, The European Community in Perspective - Foreword (Box 11)
- Monetary Committee (of the Atlantic Council of the U.S.)
  - 1973
  - 1972
  - 1971
- M
- Miscellany
  - September 1974
  - August 1974
  - July 1974
  - June 1974
  - May 1974
  - April 1974
  - 1973
  - 1971
  - 1970
- N
- North Atlantic Treaty Organization
  - Brosio, Manlio
  - General
  - NATO strategy, 1966
  - U.S. Permanent Representative to NATO
  - NATO Strategy, 1966
  - Cleveland Harlan
  - NATO: Some Practical Considerations, 1964
  - Ellsworth, Robert (Box 12)
- National Citizens Committee to Save Education and Library Funds
- Newsweek, Letter to the editor of, re Milton Friedman, The Obsolete SDR's, 1969
- O
- P
- Pennsylvania, University of - Foreign Policy Institute - Robert Strausz-Hupe
- Reunion of Group of Four, 1971
- R
- Republican Task Force on NATO
- Roosa, Robert V.
- S
- Supreme Headquarters, Allied Powers, Europe
- Stanley, Timothy - Proposal to Atlantic Treaty Association, 1971
- Sun (Baltimore), Letter to the editor of, 1971
- State, Secretary of, Letter to, 1971
- Stikker, Dirk
- T
- Trade
- Trade Panel, Special, 1973
- Trade and agriculture
- Tuthill, John W.
- Teachers College (of Columbia University) (Box 13)
  - 1975
  - 1971
  - 1970
  - 1969
- Union Interalliee
- U.S. Government and education
- V
- Atlantic Council of the U.S. meeting, Geneva, 1966
- W
- Washington Institute of Foreign Affairs
- X-Z
- 1977
- 1976
- Committee on Atlantic Studies meeting, 1970
- NATO twentieth anniversary reception, 1969
- Atlantic Treaty Association (Box 14)
  - Speakers
  - Buffet supper, 1969
- Atlantic Institute
  - Atlantic and European studies in college curricula
  - Atlantic studies meeting, 1966
- Atlantic Council of the U.S. - Report by Gene Bradley and Jay Cerf, 1967
- Williamsburg Conference, 1966
- Committee on Atlantic Studies
  - Meeting, Paris, 1969
  - Meeting, Washington, 1969
  - General
  - Grant requests and fund support
  - Meeting, Washington, 1966
  - Meeting, Washington, 1967
  - Meeting, Washington, 1968
- 1976
- Monetary institutions (Box 15)
- Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development
- Economics and capital supply
- Money
- Jordan, Robert S.
- Economic Committee
- Development
- Europe and America: The Next Ten Years, 1970 - Comments
- Security Working Group (of the Atlantic Council of the U.S.)
- Salzburg Seminars
  - General
  - 1966
  - 1970
  - 1971
- Winds of Change across the Atlantic, 1969
- Chronological
  - July-September 1971
  - September-December 1974
- Atlantic Council of the U.S.
  - General
  - Crotonville meeting, 1965
- Contributions (Box 16)
- Committee on Atlantic Studies, 1971
- A
- Alphand, Herve
- American Bankers Association
- Atlantic Community Quarterly - Correspondence
- Atlantic community
- B
- Brookings Institution
- Button, Robert E.
- C
- U
- Centre d'Information et de Documentation Atlantique
- Balance of payments
- Bank for International Settlements (Box 17)
- Bilderberg meetings
- Center for Strategic Studies (Georgetown University)
- Church, Frank
- Committee on the Plight of Soviet Jewry
- Common Market
- Critical Issues Council
- D
- E
- Eisenhower, Dwight D.
- English-Speaking Union
- European Economic Community
- F
- First National City Bank
- Foreign Policy Association
- G (Box 18)
- H
- I
- International Monetary Fund and Bank
- J
- Jacobsson (Per) Foundation
  - A Report of Progress, 1964
  - General
  - Correspondence
  - Organization, business and administration
- Jucker-Fleetwood, Erin E.
- K
- K (Box 19)
- Kirstensen, Thorkil
- Knox College
- L
- Lists
- M
- Mc
- N
- National Foreign Trade Council
- National public opinion survey on Atlantic unity
- Norstad, Lauris, Atlantic Council of the U.S. dinner for, 1963
- Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development
- O
- P
- Parliamentary and Scientific Conference, 2d, Vienna, 1964
- Press clippings
- R
- Republican Citizens Committee of the U.S.
- Republican Policy Committee
- Reserve City Bankers, Association of Robert College (Turkey) (Box 20)
- Roper, Elmo
- S
- Salzburg Seminar in American Studies
- T
- Teachers College (of Columbia University) - John Fischer
- U
- V
- W
- X-Z
- Washington Institute of Foreign Affairs
- Washington Center of Foreign Policy Research